

Michael Rukundo Knabe

Full Stack Web and App Developer

Certified Full Stack Web and App developer with a business mindset and a huge interest in innovation and new technologies. Proficient in Frontend and Backend.

Driven team-player with great communication skills and with previous experience within the tech industry through managing frontend, backend and design experts as well as third party technical service providers. Experienced in project-, product- and business development.

Contact Info

+49 173 3034474



mrknabe2@gmail.com



www.michaelknabe.com

Personal Info

10245 Berlin, Germany 29.07.1990

Key Skills

Product Management Project Management

Stakeholder Management

Problem Solving

Responsive Design JavaScript

React.js

HTML5

CSS3

Node.js

Express

APIs

Software Testing

Tools

Jira, Trello Microsoft Office Salesforce / Hubspot

Git and GitHub

Console

VS Code

Languages

German: Native English: Excellent Spanish: Fluent

Interests

Sports: Running and Fitness Music: Acoustic Guitar

Education

06/2020 - 10/2020

Berlin

09/2016 - 10/2017

Lisbon / Copenhagen

09/2015 - 10/2017

Copenhagen

10/2011 - 02/2015

Cologne

09/2007 - 06/2010 Frechen

09/2006 - 06/2007 Shaftesbury

WBS CODING SCHOOL

Certificate in Full Stack Web and App Development

Master of Science in international Management

CEMS - The Global Alliance in Management Education

Final Grade: A-

Master of Science in International Business

Copenhagen Business School

Final Grade: 1.7

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

University of Cologne

Final Grade: 2.2

A-Levels (Abitur) Final Grade: 1.7

Year Abroad

Work Experience

12/2019 - 06/2020

Berlin

Senior Business Development Manager

GoLiving

Cooperation with large real estate companies short-term for leasing, mid-term for joint project development in Berlin, Cologne and Düsseldorf

Identification of customer needs and development of suitable use cases

Creation and continuous development of a corporate pitch deck and business development playbook

05/2019 - 10/2019 Berlin

Project Manager Mobility Apps - MaaS

Mobimeo GmbH (Deutsche Bahn AG)

Strategic partner management: analysis of needs, definition of product scope & integration roadmap

Manage various teams composed of product, engineering, design and market experts

Management of external tech service providers

Highlight project risks and develop mitigation options, ensure timely delivery and compliance with SLAs

Consult partners on market entry strategy and comms strategy, train staff on products for customer service

11/2017 - 04/2019 Berlin

Partnerships Manager and Product Owner - SaaS

Telefónica Germany NEXT GmbH (Minodes)

- Product Owner White Label: product development, market analysis, development and execution of channel strategy as well as first partners ahead of schedule
- Defined product iterations based on partner requirements and internal feasibility in close collaboration with the development, operations and BI team
- Scaled up White Label to be major revenue channel
- Strategic development of partnerships from acquisition and relationship building to closing, execution of roll-outs and cross- & upselling
- Cross functional project management to ensure compliance with SLAs
- Planned and executed negotiations, onboardings and workshops with C-level executives
- Promotion from Sales Development Representative to Partnerships Manager

Internships & Volunteer Work

02/2016 - 05/2016

Copenhagen

Consultant

180 Degrees Consulting, Client: Non-Profit-Organization

- Analysed the client's organizational structure, employee incentives and fundraising strategy
- Developed and implemented new vision & mission statements, and a new organizational structure
- Created action plan to reach fundraising goals

12/2014 - 05/2015

Berlin

Business Developer

Rocket Internet SE (EatFirst)

- Set up, improved and executed operations processes
- Negotiations with business partners & suppliers
- Identification, analysis & reporting on operations KPIs

09/2013 - 12/2013 Cologne / Dortmund

Consultant

OSCAR GmbH, Client: Big Public Contractor

- Analysed the client's cost accounting processes and developed a new system for enhanced performance
- Carried out test runs of the concept
- Summary: The client's directors commissioned a follow-up project for companywide implementation

11/2011 - 09/2012

Cologne

Project Lead

AIESEC-Cologne (Student Society)

- Led a team of eight students
- Organized accommodation and internships in local NGOs for 20 volunteers from 13 nations

10/2010 - 06/2011

Madrid

Volunteer

Internationaler Bund e.V. – full-time

- Took a three months intensive Spanish course
- Worked six months as a volunteer in a kindergarten